kjwilde@wildecompany.com www.linkedin.com/in/wildekurt

Professional Summary

Controls and SCADA Engineer experienced in all aspects of the industrial control system design and implementation. Highly knowledgeable in both the hardware (wiring, CAD, UL) aspects as well as software design (PLC as well as higher level languages). Experience in numerous industries and application types.

Key Skills

Programming Visual Basic (5, 6 and .NET)

Jython, Python, Java, C, C++

PLC - Full range of Rockwell (Allen Bradley) products as well as PLC's from

Omron, GE, Mitsubishi, Automation Direct and Horner. HMI – FactoryTalk View, Wonderware, Ignition, Cmore

Web - ASP.NET, HTML

Database – MS-SQL, SQL Query, T-SQL

SCADA Inductive Automation (Gold Certified in SCADA and MES)

Wonderware InTouch Rockwell FactoryTalk

Vision Systems Keyence

Cognex

Drive Systems Single and three phase AC

Variable speed DC and AC

Servos including Kinetix 300/350 and Ultra platforms.

Design: AutoCAD and AutoCAD Electrical

Panel design including layouts, BOMs, wiring and elementary diagrams

Motor and drive sizing

Power distribution panel sizing and specifying

UL508A and NFPA 79

Basic Software Microsoft Office, PowerPoint, Access, etc.

Visual Studio

AutoCAD and AutoCAD Electrical

Education

1996-1999 DeVry Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering Technology

Graduated Summa cum Laude (GPA 3.95/4.00)

Extra course work in procedural and object oriented programming theory.

Employment

2017-Present Bastian Solutions, Inc

Senior Controls Engineer

- Involved in all aspects of control system design in the material handling industry.
- PLC programming
- SCADA design using Ignition as well as Factory Talk View
- HMI design

2015-2017 Trimax Systems, Richardson, TX Senior Controls Engineer

- Develop SCADA systems primarily using Ignition by Inductive Automation for a number of industries including Oil and Gas, Water and Waste Water Treatment, electronics manufacturing and aviation fuel distribution.
- PLC programming on various platforms including those from Rockwell and GE.
- Provide quotes and estimates for sales on engineering labor and control system hardware.

2013-2015 Applied Group, Bridgeton, MO Systems Engineer

- Programming, support and design of cloud-based SCADA systems.
- PLC programming
- Integration of Inductive Automation's Ignition SCADA system at a number of manufacturers.

2010-2013 Henniges Automotive, Keokuk, IA Senior Electrical Engineer

- Control system design for a variety of machinery including extruders, assembly machines and cut off saws.
- Supervise hourly maintenance technicians and provide technical support as necessary.
- Support manufacturing operations, continuous improvement and quality objectives.
- Develop automated server-based Kanban system.
- Develop plant-wide server-based shipping label system.
- Integrate existing manufacturing operations into a plant-wide network (Ethernet).
- Integrate plant utility (e.g. power, compressed air) monitoring into a plant-wide network.
- Support engineering servers used for data collection.

2004-2010 Vertis Communications, Baltimore, MD Electrical Engineer

- Design software and hardware for web offset printing presses and associated equipment
- Specify plant electrical distribution equipment.
- Obtain quotes and provide estimates as part of CapEx planning.
- Supervise installation and start up activities
- Provide technical support to electrical maintenance technicians in 25 manufacturing facilities.
- Develop and teach PLC training courses for maintenance technicians.

2000-2004 The Wilde Company, Chicago, IL

- Provide contract engineering services to a variety of companies in the printing, pharmaceutical, plastics and packaging industries.
- HMI and SCADA design using Visual Basic.

1999-2000 Westech Automation, Buffalo Grove, IL

- Control system design and programming for automated assembly lines used in the automotive industry.
- Startup and debug of assembly lines.

1996-1999 Controls & Automation Technologies, Chicago, IL Controls Engineer

- Integrate high speed servo systems into new and existing machinery.
- Program a wide variety of PLC and servo controllers.
- Provide installation and startup services.

References Available upon request